Thank you for coming.
Take care.
Well... what's the verdict?
Uh, they're unique.
Oh, very unique.
And did you see who we
have over there, ladies?
Wallace Stanton, the art
critic for the Atlanta Examiner.
Hm. WOMAN 2: Oh, my.
Then we'll have to appear
even more impressed.
You're really moving right
along, aren't you, Randall?
Why, Eileen, you flatter me.
Excuse me, ladies. Of course.
Such a surprise to see you here.
Thank you so much for coming.
Take care.
Janice, darling, I was
afraid you weren't coming.
Oh, you know I wouldn't
miss your opening
for the world, Randall.
Of course you wouldn't.
Where have you been?
Well, I was running
an errand. Why?
What's this?
It was going to be
a surprise. It's a gift.
It's for you, for your opening.
I needed you here now.
Randall, I set the
time-lapse camera
to go off every
15 minutes, okay?
Come on. You'll have
your portrait of the opening.
No problem.
That's not the point
and you know it.
You're supposed to be here
when I tell you to be here.
Randall, I know you're
tense. This is your big day,
but lighten up, okay?
Here.
You never learn, do you?
I never should
have taken you in.
Once that crowd is gone,
I want you to
pack up your things
and get out of here.
What?
You heard me.
Out, as in disappear.
Randall...!
Don't make a scene.
You can't just throw me out
with no reason! RANDALL: No?
You're fired! Get out!
Now!
Okay. Okay, fine.
I have to get my stuff.
Ah!
Come back later.
Kids.
Where'd you get your
hands on stuff like this?
How much?
Two hundred and fifty.
Are you serious?
Take it or leave it.
I'll take it.
All right.
This one's got film
in it. You want it?
The film!
You the girl who lives here?
Amy Adler?
Is your picture in here?
Come on!
Jones, take the front.
Hey, Charlie.
Yes, sir.
I just got a new
driver's license.
Now, don't look at the name.
Now, if you didn't
know who that is,
who would you
say that looks like?
It looks like you.
Well, I don't think
that looks like me.
I think it looks maybe like
some guy from Wisconsin.
Cup of coffee, Charlie.
Oh, sure, Bill. Hey, Bill.
Now, don't look at the name.
Who would you
say that looks like?
It looks like you.
Well, I'm damned if I
think it looks like me.
My eyes are all off to the side
like I'm trying to see
the back of my head,
and my mouth's open
and I got scowl on my face
like I smell something.
Well?
Coffee, Charlie.
Sure, judge.
Now, judge, don't
look at the name.
Who would you
say that looks like?
Looks like you.
Oh, come on, judge.
Well, it does.
Well, I'll tell
you what I think.
I think half the
fellows in this state
that are running around loose
are running around loose
because they don't look like
their pictures on
their driver's license.
Cop go to pick him up,
they don't know who they are.
Yeah, yeah. WOMAN: Mr. Matlock!
Mr. Matlock!
Mr. Matlock? Yes, ma'am?
I need to talk to you.
Well, are you all right?
What can I do for you?
I need a lawyer right
now. Now, wait a minute...
I hear you're the
best lawyer in Atlanta.
W-w-well, miss...
I'm Amy Adler, and
I am in a real jam.
The cops think I killed my boss.
Well, I'm sorry, miss.
Look, Mr. Matlock,
I have a juvenile
delinquent rap sheet.
If I don't get
somebody like you,
I don't stand a chance.
I did not kill him.
Excuse me, Ben.
Is, uh, this your client?
No.
Well, you're gonna have
to come with us, Miss Adler.
You know, if I hadn't
come looking for you,
I could have been
out of town by now!
We cop a plea and
you get five to ten years
with good behavior.
But I didn't do it.
Count your blessings.
A hostile jury could
stick you with life,
so cop a plea.
Don't cop a plea.
Good morning, Alan.
Hi, Ben.
You must be busy.
I'll take this one.
Since when are you
into pro bono, Ben?
I've seen the
color of her money.
State v. Amy Adler.
Case number A1217798.
Benjamin Matlock for
the defense, Your Honor
That's us.
So why did you change your mind?
Oh, I don't know.
Snap judgment. A hunch.
Good for my image.
Think I made a mistake?
You checked me out.
Yeah.
You do have a juvenile
delinquent rap sheet.
So far, nothing major.
So, what about your fee?
What about it?
I've got $250. You want it now?
You better hang on to that.
I don't want you to have to
steal to get something to eat.
Where'd you get it?
Pawned some stuff.
Now, listen, you have
to be straight right now.
Real straight.
And the worst thing you could do
would be to leave Atlanta.
I'm not gonna run away.
I just thought I'd mention it.
Ben.
Can I have a word with you?
Now, look, I don't know
how she talked you into this,
but she is trouble
with a capital T.
Maybe.
Ben, why are you doing this?
Well, it's just...
one of those deals. It's...
You remember a few years ago,
when the Johnson boy
came through here on the run?
Yeah. Yeah.
Remember there had
been a robbery with a gun?
Yeah. He said he hadn't done it.
Yeah, we didn't take
the case. That's right.
He got five years,
and he hadn't done it.
Yeah.
Well, she's a runner.
And this time she didn't run.
All right. Well, you got
your hands full this time.
The DA's got enough
evidence to lock her up
and throw away the key.
Like what?
Now, you got an eyewitness
who saw her enter the building
at 10:00 that evening.
What else? Oh, not much.
Just a photograph
that shows your client
holding the murder weapon,
leaning over the dead body.
Where'd that come from?
Right there.
Yeah.
Sequence photography.
The camera's set to go off
automatically every 15 minutes.
Huh.
Well, what was it
taking pictures of?
Everything.
He was doing a series
sequence of the opening.
Time-lapse photography.
You mean people actually
pay money for this stuff?
Up to $5,000 a pop.
What do you know about the fella
who says he saw you
coming in here that night?
Well, he runs the
bakery across the street.
Huh. Yeah.
But you said you
came up the back stairs.
I did.
Well, if he was over here
and you came in over there,
how could he see you?
Well, he couldn't.
No.
He must have seen
some other woman.
You think any of the
women at the party
would want to kill
Randall Brooks?
I don't think so.
Well, one of them could
have seen your fight with him
and hope you'd get
blamed for his murder.
A lot of people
had left by then.
Just a few stayed.
I know three of the
women that were here,
but they're crazy about him.
Yeah? Yeah.
They were buying his
stuff even before the show.
They'd call and buy
it over the phone.
Sight unseen?
Yeah, Randall used to
call them his patron saints.
Huh.
We'll need their
names and addresses.
They're locked up
in the filing cabinet.
You know where there's a key?
No, I don't.
Well... Just a second.
Hm.
What happened?
Here's the names and
addresses of those three women.
Did you find the key?
No.
Thought they were locked.
They were.
Sort of.
Not completely.
Not effectively.
So these women bought
this stuff sight unseen, huh?
Yep.
Well, maybe I can find out why.
Go down to Patton's
and pick yourself out
a dress for court.
I don't think I
could afford one.
Unless you want
me to steal one. I...
No. No stealing.
Put it on my account.
Well, how am I gonna...?
We'll talk about it.
That's nice.
Yeah, that's good.
Sweet, like the girl next door.
And cut. Whitney, take five.
Gesundheit.
What?
I say gesundheit on that sneeze.
Oh... Oh, thank you.
I guess I'm allergic
to that perfume.
But it'll be worth it if
you get the job, huh?
Do I know you?
Oh, I'm Ben Matlock,
Amy Adler's lawyer.
Oh. I understand that you were
quite a fan of Randall Brooks.
Yes, I think that someday
his pictures are going to be
worth a lot of money.
Oh.
Well, I... I have to
be honest with you.
I... I never
considered a sandwich
a very important thing
to take a picture of.
Maybe trees or flowers or
the recherché cosmetics girl.
Well, thank you.
I haven't been selected yet,
but I appreciate the thought.
Uh, tell me, Miss Seaver,
you didn't go back
to Mr. Brooks' loft
after the murder, did you?
No. No, I was at
the Haverly Club
until 3 in the morning.
Oh.
A lot of people
saw you, I suppose.
Yes, of course.
Maybe you could give
me some of their names.
Whitney. Oh, excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Interesting, aren't they?
Um... yes.
Please. Oh, thank you.
Randall did them for me
when I took over as
headmistress here at Fairmont.
Oh.
But I'm certain that
you're not here for
a dissertation on
art, Mr. Matlock.
Well, no. Actually, I need
to ask you a few questions.
Ask away.
The last time I was
in the principal's office,
I got my ears boxed
for impertinence.
Of course that was
quite a few years ago.
Well, I promise you it
won't happen this time.
Okay.
Uh, you see,
I think a woman
killed Randall Brooks.
And, well, at the risk of
being impertinent again,
where were you the
night of the murder?
The evening of the 17th?
Let's see.
I was at... the
Junior Charities Ball.
There were lots
of photographers.
I'm sure there must
be many pictures.
I must be in some of them.
Well, as they say,
a picture's worth
a thousand words.
Yes. They are.
I've already told everything
to, uh, Lieutenant Davis.
I know this is a bad
time, Miss Warden,
but I've got to
get to the bottom
of this Randall Brooks murder,
and I need your help.
There's nothing really
that I can help you with.
I don't suppose
you had any reason
to go back to
the loft that night?
Mr. Matlock, I've told
Lieutenant Davis everything.
You wouldn't happen to remember
where were you that evening?
At a rally until midnight.
If you don't believe me, you
can check with the TV stations.
It's all on tape. Now,
if you'll excuse me,
I do have a press conference
I have to make in five minutes.
What do you think?
Well...
You know what? It was
on sale. Half price. See?
Half price, huh? Mm-hm.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have alibis
fresh from the police darkroom.
Eileen Middleton.
Courtesy of our local
television station,
Janice Warden.
They both check out, Ben.
What about Whitney Seaver?
Now, she says she
was at the Haverly Club,
but I have not been
able to confirm it.
Well, let's cash it in.
Tyler will take you
by to get your stuff.
Tonight, stay at the Y.
Why can't I stay at the loft?
Because it's the
scene of the crime.
Could be dangerous.
You still afraid I'll run?
I never said that.
Just stay at the Y.
Hey, Tyler.
Yeah?
Look at this driver's license.
Now don't... Don't
look at the name.
Think that looks like me?
That looks better than you.
There you are.
Next.
I'd like to see about getting
a new driver's license.
All right. You have your
old license with you?
There.
This is a new license, sir.
I know.
The problem is the picture.
What about it?
Well, it doesn't look like me.
Yes, it does.
Ma'am, I've shown that
picture to all my friends
and none of them
think it looks like me.
Sir, I cannot give
you a new license.
Well, couldn't I just
have my picture retaken?
I'll pay for it.
That's not the point.
We can't go around
redoing driver's licenses
for everyone who doesn't
like the way they look.
Well... Well, no, that's
not... Not the point.
See, this is my
old driver's license.
See the difference?
Oh. Yeah.
Yeah.
You look younger.
We can't fix that.
Next.
Okay. I'll just be a second.
I have to get a
few things, all right?
I'll be right here. Okay.
Oh!
Are you all right? Yeah.
He wrecked my dress.
Never mind that. Did you
get a good look at him?
I got his picture.
Yeah.
Well, well.
Hm.
You shouldn't have
come up here by yourself.
I know.
Tyler tell you I
ruined my dress?
Yeah.
I guess it's pretty clear though
that I didn't kill
Randall Brooks, huh?
Well, the trick is to
make that clear to the jury.
Do you think I stand a chance?
I don't like to
make predictions.
It sure would help if we knew
what this fella was looking for.
Anything in here worth stealing?
There's equipment,
but he wasn't after that.
And there was a cigar
box with some cash in it.
Was there a safe?
No.
The only thing Randall
ever kept locked up
were his reviews.
He was going to donate them
to the Smithsonian someday.
Think they're here?
Yeah.
Where'd you learn to do that?
You don't want to know.
Huh! Figures he'd only
save the good ones.
I can't fault him for that.
Wow.
Janice Warden?
Hey.
Come on, I've seen nudes before.
I'm an artist.
Ooh.
Whitney Seaver?
Eileen Middleton?
That's nice lighting.
Ooh.
Why would three proper ladies
allow pictures like
this to be made?
Don't know.
These negatives were
taken at least ten years ago.
Hm.
Whew, good-looking women.
Guess that explains
why they're buying his pictures.
Randall Brooks was something.
He got money and a reputation
for being a fine
artist from blackmail.
That's some scheme.
Mm-hm.
The ledger says that he got
three $5,000 payments
each month for
the past six months,
but last month only two
payments were made.
Hm.
One of his patron
saints didn't pay.
Major breakthrough here.
Once again, hard work
and experience have paid off.
I have a lead on the
darkroom assailant.
Someone recognized him
from the photos I took last night?
Not quite so simple.
Take a look at the
design on that T-shirt.
All I see is a
triangle in a circle.
To the uninformed eye, perhaps,
but to the trained eye,
that design is the symbol of
a prominent local athletic club.
And with a little persuasion,
which you will find
itemized in my expenses,
I convinced the
management to supply me with
a name and an address.
Go to it, Tyler.
Amy... Hm?
Keep him company.
I'm never out of sight
of either one of you.
Well, we both need you.
Right now it's Tyler's turn.
Where you going?
To see if I can pick
up a little extra change.
Mr. Matlock, I've already
told you everything I know
about Randall Brooks.
Well, I'm... I'm not here
to talk about the murder.
No? No.
See, I've become a
real fan of Mr. Brooks,
especially some
of his earlier works.
You think your
board of directors
might appreciate fine art?
What is it you want?
Well, the way I figure it,
these must be worth a
lot more than those shoes.
Mr. Matlock, you earn
hundreds of thousands of dollars
defending your clients.
Why would you jeopardize that
for a penny-ante
blackmail scheme?
Well, for one reason,
I'm working free this week.
And who said it was penny ante?
Get out of here.
And I'm warning you,
I'll have you disbarred.
Okay.
Ruin your career
at the same time.
Shut the door.
Five thousand dollars.
That's what I was
paying Randall.
I thought art was supposed
to appreciate with time.
How much?
Oh, say... another 5.
Ten thousand dollars.
On second thought,
these are free.
Hey.
Haven't we met someplace before?
What are you doing here?
You broke into Randall
Brooks' loft last night, Mr. Jacobs.
I just wanted to know why.
Why don't you get out of
here before I call the cops?
Go get him.
Tell you one thing,
you've got a nice smile.
How much will it
take for you to, uh,
misplace these things?
Well... I tend to
be very organized.
Three thousand dollars.
You know, this would
make a very neat poster.
Five thousand.
I was reading about
this huge campaign fund
you've built up.
Ten thousand.
That's my limit.
Ten thousand dollars?
Mm-hm.
Thanks for being so helpful.
On the house.
Very, very nice.
Now, look right at me
and tell me what
you did last night.
Okay, tell me again.
Tell me again.
One more time.
Again.
Give me some more!
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Okay, hold on.
All right, I have to reload.
Excuse me one moment.
You're gonna be
making a lot of money
if you get this contract.
I'm sorry, no sale.
I wonder what your
boss will think of these.
This is wrong.
I won't be blackmailed anymore.
Is that what you
told Randall Brooks?
What are you talking about?
I sort of figured
it had to be you.
Somebody didn't pay
Randall Brooks last month.
I have a hunch whoever
stopped paying him
is the same person
that killed him.
See you in court.
Mr. Matlock.
Do you remember that I told you
I was at the Haverly Club
the night of the murder?
I remember you
couldn't prove it.
Well, here you have it.
My picture while I was there.
Thank you.
Oh, you're very welcome.
I was sure it was
Whitney Seaver.
I was absolutely sure
it was Whitney Seaver.
Then she comes up
with an airtight alibi.
So now we're right
back where we started.
It had to be Whitney Seaver.
She's the only one
who didn't come
across with the money.
She didn't come
across with the money
because she didn't
have the money.
But Ben, how could she be in
two places at the same time?
I don't know. Mm.
One more time.
Okay, hold it, hold it.
I Like that. One more.
Ah, that's it.
Thank you, ladies.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Bye. Mwah.
Bye-bye. Bye.
Good luck. Take care.
Okay.
God. Ow.
Where'd you get these negatives?
Jacobs' darkroom.
How'd you get in there?
You know.
Come on, I thought
you'd be excited.
I am.
But when this is over,
I want you to forget
how to pick locks.
But now we know Whitney Seaver
doesn't have an alibi.
In a court of law,
it's not enough to know
somebody committed a crime.
You have to prove it.
We still can't place
Whitney Seaver in the loft
at the time of the murder.
I know she was there.
She had to be there.
Can you make an
enlargement of this?
Sure, yeah.
Bigger.
That's it.
Mr. Jacobs, would
you tell the court
what you do for a living.
I'm a photographer.
And what kinds of things
do you photograph?
Fashion, mostly.
I do, uh, layouts for
magazines. Things like that.
I guess you get to work
with a lot of pretty girls.
Somebody's got to do it.
You know a model
named Whitney Seaver?
I've heard the name.
Answer the question.
Do you know Whitney Sea...? Yes.
Uh, you and, uh, Whitney Seaver
are having a
relationship, isn't it true?
Objection. The details of
Mr. Jacobs' personal life
have no bearing on
these proceedings.
Your Honor, I can show relevancy
if you'll allow me to continue.
Objection overruled.
Proceed, Mr. Matlock.
Thank you.
Isn't it true that you
are having a relationship
with Whitney Seaver?
Yes.
Have you ever photographed her?
Yes, of course.
Your Honor, at this time,
I'd like to show this witness
and the court some slides
made from these negatives
which counsel for the
state and Your Honor
previewed with me this
morning in chambers.
So noted.
I had these slides made
so we could all see better.
- Dim the lights, please.
- For the record,
we object to this procedure.
Your Honor,
this will be a lot easier,
cleaner and faster
than passing around a
bunch of photographs.
I'm going to allow it.
Gentlemen, dim
the lights, please.
There you go.
Thank you.
Now, Mr. Jacobs,
did you take this picture
at the Haverly Club?
Yes.
Okay. Did you take this
photograph of Whitney Seaver?
Well, did you take it?
Yes.
Okay, did you take this picture?
No.
This is the photograph
that Whitney Seaver gave me
to prove that she was
at the Haverly Club
the night of the murder.
This is a composite of
the other two pictures,
isn't it, Mr. Jacobs?
I wouldn't know.
Tell me, Mr. Jacobs,
why is the shadow
on the right side of
Miss Seaver's face
and on the left of
everyone else's?
How should I know?
Because, sir, you
manufactured this picture
in your darkroom to give
Whitney Seaver an alibi
for the night of the murder.
That's not true.
Miss Seaver was not at
the Haverly Club that night.
This photograph
is a complete fake,
isn't it, Mr. Jacobs?
Objection. Asked and answered.
No further questions.
Cross-examine, Mr. Houghton.
No questions, Your Honor.
Step down, Mr. Jacobs.
Mr. Matlock, you may
call your next witness.
Defense calls Whitney
Seaver to the stand.
Congratulations.
I understand that
after a year's search,
a cosmetics company
has chosen you
as their spokesperson.
Yes, I feel very fortunate.
And I understand this company
sets the highest standards
for their representatives,
who, like Caesar's wife,
must be above reproach.
That's right.
So how much are they paying you?
I don't know yet.
I spoke with a Mr. Levine
from the company,
and he says that with,
uh, your endorsements
and salary and
television and all,
the job will be
worth, uh, $300,000.
Well, I'm sure
Mr. Levine would know.
So this contract
is your big break.
Yes, it certainly is.
I understand that
you were quite a fan
of the decedent's work.
Randall Brooks was a
brilliant photographer.
I have here
some photographs
that Randall Brooks took of you.
Do you know what
I'm talking about?
No.
Well, I could show them to you
to refresh your
memory, but if I do that,
I'll have to show them
to the prosecutor and the judge,
and I don't want
to do that, but I will.
Now, tell me,
Randall Brooks took
some pictures of you
that you wouldn't
want your daddy to see
and was blackmailing
you, wasn't he?
Yes.
Randall Brooks
was blackmailing you
because you were
afraid these pictures
would ruin your
modeling contract.
Yes.
I don't think it's fair
for a person to hold something
over another person's
head for all this time
that wasn't even
a crime, do you?
No, I don't.
No. You know
what else isn't fair?
For somebody to
go to prison for life
for something they didn't do.
Now, isn't it true
that last month when
you couldn't pay,
you were afraid
that Randall Brooks
would publish these
pictures, so you killed him?
Objection.
Sustained.
Mr. Matlock, this court
is interested in fact,
not hypothesis.
You Honor, that's just
what I was getting to,
but I need an answer.
All right. Proceed.
Thank you.
Isn't it true you killed
Randall Brooks?
No.
Your Honor, I'm gonna
have to dim the lights again.
Go ahead.
Now, we'll call these
Defense Exhibit G
for identification.
These are time-lapsed
photographs
taken the afternoon
Mr. Brooks was murdered.
You didn't know these pictures
were being taken, did you?
I, uh... I don't think you did.
Now, the police have
numbered these photographs,
so we'll know exactly in
which order they were taken.
For the record,
this is a photograph
of the defendant
kneeling over the deceased.
The defense stipulates
to that, Your Honor.
That's not what
I was driving at.
Miss Seaver, you see
this object right here?
You know what that is?
I have no idea.
Well, let's take a closer look.
Now, what's that look
like to you, Miss Seaver?
Uh, I don't know. It
could be an earring.
It sure looks like
an earring to me.
Now, let's take a look
at the next photograph
in the series.
You see the defendant is gone.
The object is still there.
Now, the next photograph,
taken a few minutes later.
The object is gone.
Miss Seaver,
could that object be
an earring that belongs to you?
No. This is ridiculous.
Let's take another look
at the party in
Randall Brooks' loft
before he was murdered.
Is that a picture of
you, Miss Seaver?
Yes. So what?
Let's take a closer look.
See there?
Even closer.
See?
Now the object on the floor.
Now you.
Looks like a matched set to me.
You know what I think?
I think you lost your earring
in your struggle
with Randall Brooks,
and when Amy
Adler entered the loft,
you hid.
And you had to
wait till she left
to pick up your earring.
You were in the loft after
Amy left, weren't you?
And you did kill Randall
Brooks, didn't you?
No further questions.
We find the defendant,
Amy Adler, not guilty.
The defendant
being found not guilty.
This court is adjourned.
Well, we did it, huh? Yeah.
Oh, you want your
$250 right now?
Uh, you... You keep that.
You are a good photographer?
Well, yeah.
Do you think you could retouch
my driver's license picture?
www.tvsubtitles.net